<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://luni-4.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://luni-4.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-04-15T23:02:40+00:00</updated><id>https://luni-4.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Peculiar Random Thoughts</title><subtitle>Ramblings of an open source amateur.
</subtitle><author><name>Luni-4</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Pole Game</title><link href="https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2023/06/14/polegame.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Pole Game" /><published>2023-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2023/06/14/polegame</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2023/06/14/polegame.html"><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>Pole Game</strong> is a simple amateur game created some years ago by me and
my group of friends during a friend’s birthday in the early days of September.</p>

<p>We wanted to relax after a quite physical-intensive game, so we had decided to
make some soccer passes in the garden. Our friend’s house contains an high
electricity pole in the middle of the garden, and the mental enlightenment
came up when one of us accidentally threw the ball against that pole.</p>

<p>“Why do not we create a game which mixes football passes with this pole?”, he
said the birthday boy, and so it was, one minute later we had created the rules
of this simple and funny game.</p>

<p>Only <strong>two</strong> objects are required to play this game:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A pole, or a tree, in short, something which is thick and tall. Personally,
I would not recommend a tree as pole though, because the repeating act of
throwing a ball against its trunk, in the long run, it might ruin its bark</li>
  <li>Any kind of ball which does not break when kicked with the feet</li>
</ul>

<p>The winner is the player who first gains at least <strong>10</strong> points.</p>

<p>You score points when you hit the pole with the ball. If the pole is hit from
a distance greater than 3 meters, then you get <strong>3</strong> points, otherwise
<strong>1</strong> point. The distance which allows to get <strong>3</strong> points <strong>can</strong> be modified
by players at the beginning of a match.</p>

<p>You can approximately calculate the distance from the pole using as reference
points some objects present in the place where you are playing.</p>

<p>The Pole Game is subdivided in rounds and every round is composed of turns: one
for each player. The number of rounds is not defined and that depends only on
the time needed for one of the players to gain at least 10 points.</p>

<p>To assign a turn to each player, thus decreeing a playing order, the rule is
simple: starting from a random order, whoever kicks the pole first, starts
first. This initial round has been called the <strong>choice round</strong>.</p>

<p>After the <em>choice round</em> has been finished, it starts the real game following by
the established order. In a turn, a player can <strong>only</strong> kick the ball <strong>once</strong> and it
<strong>must</strong> be kicked exactly from the <strong>same</strong> position wherein the previous
player has thrown it.
As soon as the ball hits or misses the pole, the turn of the next player starts.</p>

<p>When the new position makes the ball impossible to kick, you can can shift the
ball a little with your feet. If the other players consider your shift too
advantageous, you need to move the ball back to the original position and shift
it again until an overall agreement is reached.</p>

<p>A little advice, be smart and kick the ball really hard! In this way, when it
bounces backs after having kicked the pole, it takes unpredictable directions,
putting the following player in difficulty!</p>

<p>As other amateur games, even this one has been subjected to variants during
the time. Each of the ones shown below can be combined together without
any particular problem.</p>

<ul>
  <li>The match ends when <strong>all</strong> players have gained at least 10 points.
This rule has the objective of creating a ranking among players, so a player
has finished playing only when 10 or more points have been scored.</li>
  <li>If the ball stops too close to the pole, it will be easier for a player
scoring points. To avoid this kind of case, a minimum distance can be set.
When the ball goes beyond this allowed minimum distance, it <strong>must</strong> be
positioned <strong>exactly</strong> at the minimum distance. This variant has been created
with the purpose of having a more balanced match in terms of difficulty.
To make the minimum distance always visible, one solution could be to draw
a circle around the pole.</li>
  <li>The ball <strong>must not</strong> be kicked <strong>exactly</strong> from the <strong>same</strong> position wherein
the previous player has thrown it. A player can immediately kick the ball as
soon as it misses or hits the pole, making the entire game more rapid and fluid.</li>
  <li>If the pole is hit <strong>above</strong> a certain height, the points scored in that turn are
doubled. In our case, since the pole is 6 meters high, we have decided to set
the height threshold to 3 meters. This decision can be taken at the beginning of
a match or during its progress.</li>
  <li>If the pole presents some anomalies on its surface, for example the presence
of moss patches, a player can decide to aim at those anomalies to double the
possible points scored in that turn. Before kicking the ball, the
player <strong>must</strong> decree out loud the intent of hitting an anomaly, otherwise
the points will not be doubled!</li>
</ul>

<p>And that is all!</p>

<p>If you wish to save the rules of this game somewhere, I also provide a
downloadable version both in
<a href="https://luni-4.github.io/pdfs/english/polegame.pdf">English</a> and
<a href="https://luni-4.github.io/pdfs/italian/polegame.pdf">Italian</a> language.</p>

<p>Have fun playing this exciting game!</p>]]></content><author><name>Luni-4</name></author><category term="fun" /><category term="general" /><category term="game" /><category term="rules" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Pole Game is a simple amateur game created some years ago by me and my group of friends during a friend’s birthday in the early days of September.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SchiacciaSette</title><link href="https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2023/04/14/schiacciasette.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SchiacciaSette" /><published>2023-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2023/04/14/schiacciasette</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2023/04/14/schiacciasette.html"><![CDATA[<p>I have always wanted to find a space to share with others the games I and
my friends have been kept inventing or improving over the years.
So I said to myself: why not blog posts?!</p>

<p>As first playful post, I have chosen a game which accompanied many of our
summers at lake. I hope you can enjoy playing it with your loved ones the
same way which entertained us.</p>

<p>If you wish to save these game’s rules somewhere, I also provide a downloadable
version both in
<a href="https://luni-4.github.io/pdfs/english/schiacciasette.pdf">English</a> and
<a href="https://luni-4.github.io/pdfs/italian/schiacciasette.pdf">Italian</a> language.</p>

<p>And now have fun reading about this exciting game!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>SchiacciaSette</strong>, in English <strong>SmashSeven</strong>, is an amateur game which is
typically played, especially during the Italian summer periods, in outdoor areas
such as beaches, mountain meadows, gardens, and even in shallow waters
near sea and lake shores.</p>

<p>To play this game, a light weight and aerodynamic ball is necessary. This kind
of ball allows any player to partecipate without great difficulty since it makes
passing and throwing actions much easier. It is good practice, when it is
possible, to inflate the ball before the beginning of a match.</p>

<p>SchiacciaSette’s rules are quite simple.<br />
Players are standing in circle and <strong>must</strong> use only two of the six
volleyball skills to pass the ball to other players: <em>jump sets</em> and
<em>pass</em>.<br />
At the seven touch, the player with the ball <strong>can</strong> perform an <strong>attack</strong>,
renamed <strong>smash</strong> in this case, towards another player to eliminate that player
from the game.<br />
The winner is the last player when <strong>all</strong> other players have been eliminated.</p>

<p>The first touch of the sequence <strong>must</strong> be announced out loud yelling
the word: <strong>One</strong>. The player who forgets to pronounce that word is
automatically out of game.<br />
The following touches <strong>must not</strong> be announced out loud.<br />
When the sequence of touches is interrupted for whatever reason: the ball hits
a surface or it is intentionally stopped by a player, then the sequence <strong>must</strong>
start again from scratch.</p>

<p>If the player attacked by a smash is able to block the ball in some way,
the player who had performed the smash is eliminated.</p>

<p>When a player pronounces a number different from the word <strong>One</strong>
during the sequence of touches, that player is eliminated.</p>

<p>When the ball does not touch any body part, but any other kind of surface, if
requested by one of the players, the number associated to a failed touch
<strong>must</strong> be said out loud. If the correct number cannot be remembered, a player
is eliminated. But be careful, both the first and seventh
touch <strong>must</strong> never be declared out loud, otherwise, even in that case,
a player is eliminated.</p>

<p>This game requires <strong>at least</strong> two players in order to be played. There is not
any restriction about the maximum number of players. The more they are
involved, the longer a match will last.</p>

<p>Several variants of this game have been invented during the years and even I,
along with my friends, have drawn up a new set of rules which, on one hand it
enriches the game making the game funnier, while on the other hand, try to solve
some ambiguities to make it more accurate but without excessively increasing
its complexity.</p>

<h1 id="an-innovative-variant">An innovative variant</h1>

<p>This variant has been created to overcome some blind spots which
could lead to ambiguities or even cheating attitudes in the worst case.
The additional rules have been defined and improved starting from the
observations collected during various game matches played along the years.</p>

<p>Our own variant presents the following rules:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>You have more than one life, <strong>at least</strong> three. When the number of players is
low, this rule lengthens considerably the duration of the game and at the same
time makes the game funnier because you do not die at the first hit.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>When only two players are left, both of them are declared winners. This rule
has been added because, over the time, the sequence of seven touches among
two players had become very boring.
Another possibility might be to reduce the sequence of touches from seven to
five, or even three, but this option has never been seriously taken into
consideration in our matches, although perfectly valid.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>You <strong>should</strong> not smash against the player who performs the sixth touch,
called the <strong>setter</strong>, otherwise you lose one life. At first, this rule,
already present in other variants, had been added as a metaphorical
acknowledgment for a setter who lifts the ball,
but over the time this rule has turned into a double-edged sword because
setters started to physically throw themselves towards the seventh-touch
players to make them lose one life. This rule though has been kept unchanged
because it considerably enriches the game, forcing a player to decide,
according to the context, whether to smash or otherwise drop the ball if a
setter is going to act mischievously.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A player <strong>cannot</strong> ask you the failed number <strong>after</strong> the beginning of your
next action.</p>

    <p>If you decide to show the correct number with hands, without saying any word
or else pronouncing a completely wrong number, you do not lose any life,
because gestures supersede voice. At first, this rule seems really strange,
but it has been added not to constantly stopping the conversations, since it
this game has been used to socialize with other people as well.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>You can touch the ball more times without having to pass it to other players.
This series of touches <strong>always</strong> counts as one touch. But be careful,
you <strong>cannot</strong> perform this trick at the seventh touch, otherwise the
sequence of touches is deemed invalid and you <strong>must</strong> start that again
from scratch.<br />
At the seventh touch, you <strong>must</strong> smash as soon as you get the ball.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>If you are playing in shallow waters nearby shores, you <strong>cannot</strong>
immerse yourself into the water to avoid being hit, neither partially
nor completely. You <strong>cannot</strong> even swim away. If you do not respect these
rules, you lose one of your life as a penalty.<br />
When you play in the water, you should stand on your feet
as much as possible.<br />
You can jump into the water to avoid the ball though.</p>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Luni-4</name></author><category term="fun" /><category term="general" /><category term="game" /><category term="rules" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have always wanted to find a space to share with others the games I and my friends have been kept inventing or improving over the years. So I said to myself: why not blog posts?!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greetings!</title><link href="https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2021/01/29/greetings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greetings!" /><published>2021-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2021/01/29/greetings</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://luni-4.github.io/fun/2021/01/29/greetings.html"><![CDATA[<p>Greetings, guys!</p>

<p>What an honour, this is my first post on a blog!</p>

<p>I opened up this blog to share my knowledge of multimedia and describe some of the projects I worked on.</p>

<p>At the same time, I’m going to write down posts about history and science.</p>

<p>I hope you will enjoy your time here! See you soon, stay tuned!</p>]]></content><author><name>Luni-4</name></author><category term="fun" /><category term="general" /><category term="me" /><category term="programming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greetings, guys!]]></summary></entry></feed>